<article>
	<preamble>ACL2004-HEADLINE.pdf</preamble>
	<title>Hybrid Headlines: Combining Topics and Sentence CompressionDavid Zajic, Bonnie Dorr, Stacy President</title>
	<authors>not implemented yet</authors>
	<abstract>Abstract This paper presents Topiary, a headline- generation system that creates very short, informative summaries for news stories by combining sentence compres- sion and unsupervised topic discovery. We will show that the combination of linguistically motivated sentence com- pression with statistically selected topic terms performs better than either alone, according to some automatic summary evaluation measures. In addition we de- scribe experimental results establishing an appropriate extrinsic task on which to measure the effect of summarization on human performance. We demonstrate the usefulness of headlines in compar- ison to full texts in the context of this extrinsic task.</abstract>
	<reference>
Sabine Bergler, René Witte, Michelle Khalife,
Zhuoyan Li, and Frank Rudzicz. 2003. Using
knowledge-poorcoreference resolution for text sum-
marization. In Proceedings of the 2003 Document
Understanding Conference, Draft Papers, pages 85–
92, Edmonton, Candada.
Bonnie Dorr, David Zajic, and Richard Schwartz.
2003a. Cross-language headline generation for
hindi. ACM Transactions on Asian Language Infor-
mation Processing (TALIP), 2:2.
Bonnie Dorr, David Zajic, and Richard Schwartz.
2003b. Hedge trimmer: A parse-and-trim approach
to headline generation. In Proceedings of the HLT-
NAACL 2003 Text Summarization Workshop, Ed-
monton, Alberta, Canada, pages 1–8.
T. Euler. 2002. Tailoring text using topic words: Se-
lection and compression. In Proceedings of 13th
International Workshop on Database and Expert
Systems Applications (DEXA 2002), 2-6 Septem-
ber 2002, Aix-en-Provence, France, pages 215–222.
IEEE Computer Society.
Kevin Knight and Daniel Marcu. 2000. Statistics-
based summarization – step one: Sentence com-
pression. In The 17th National Conference of
the American Association for Artificial Intelligence
AAAI2000, Austin, Texas.
David Lewis. 1992. An evaluation of phrasal and clus-
tered representations on a text categorization task.
In Proceedings of the 15th annual international
ACM SIGIR conference on Research and develop-
ment in information retrieval, pages 37–50, Copen-
hagen, Denmark.
Chin-Yew Lin and Eduard Hovy. 2003. Auto-
matic Evaluation of Summaries Using N-gram Co-
Occurrences Statistics. In Proceedings of the Con-
ference of the North American Chapter of the As-
sociation for Computational Linguistics, Edmonton,
Alberta.
Ingrid Mårdh. 1980. Headlinese: On the Grammar of
English Front Page Headlines. Malmo.
S. Miller, M. Crystal, H. Fox, L. Ramshaw,
R. Schwartz, R. Stone, and R. Weischedel. 1998.
Algorithms that Learn to Extract Information; BBN:
Description of the SIFT System as Used for MUC-7.
In Proceedings of the MUC-7.
K. Papineni, S. Roukos, T. Ward, and W. Zhu. 2002.
Bleu: a Method for Automatic Evaluation of Ma-
chine Translation. In Proceedings of Association of
Computational Linguistics, Philadelphia, PA.
R. Schwartz, T. Imai, F. Jubala, L. Nguyen, and
J. Makhoul. 1997. A maximum likelihood model
for topic classification of broadcast news. In
Eurospeech-97, Rhodes, Greece.
David Zajic, Bonnie Dorr, Richard Schwartz, and Stacy
President. 2004. Headline evaluation experiment
results, umiacs-tr-2004-18. Technical report, Uni-
versity of Maryland Institute for Advanced Comput-
ing Studies, College Park, Maryland.
Liang Zhou and Eduard Hovy. 2003. Headline sum-
marization at isi. In Proceedings of the 2003 Doc-
ument Understanding Conference, Draft Papers,
pages 174–178, Edmonton, Candada.
</reference>
</article>
