<article>
	<preamble>compression.pdf</preamble>
	<title>Multi-Candidate Reduction: Sentence Compression as a Tool forDocument Summarization Tasks∗</title>
	<authors>not implemented yet</authors>
	<abstract>Abstract This article examines the application of two single-document sentence compression techniques to the problem of multi-document summarization—a “parse-and-trim” approach and a statisti- cal noisy-channel approach. We introduce the Multi-Candidate Reduction (MCR) framework for multi-document summarization, in which many compressed candidates are generated for each source sentence. These candidates are then selected for inclusion in the final summary based on a com- bination of static and dynamic features. Evaluations demonstrate that sentence compression is a valuable component of a larger multi-document summarization framework. Keywords: headline generation, summarization, parse-and-trim, Hidden Markov Model PACS: Artificial intelligence, 07.05.Mh; Computer science and technology, 89.20.Ff; Spoken lan- guages, processing of, 43.71.Sy</abstract>
	<reference>
L. Bahl, F. Jelinek, and R. Mercer. 1983. A maximum likelihood approach to continuous speech
recognition. IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence, 5(2):179–190.
M. Banko, V. Mittal, and M. Witbrock. 2000. Headline generation based on statistical translation.
In Proceedings of the 38th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL
2000), pages 318–325, Hong Kong.
R. Barzilay, N. Elhadad, and K. McKeown. 2002. Inferring strategies for sentence ordering in multi-
document news summarization. Journal of Artificial Intelligence Research, 17:35–55.
L. Baum. 1972. An inequality and associated maximization technique in statistical estimation of
probabilistic functions of a Markov process. Inequalities, 3:1–8.
S. Bergler, R. Witte, M. Khalife, Z. Li, and F. Rudzicz. 2003. Using knowledge-poor coreference
resolution for text summarization. In Proceedings of the HLT-NAACL 2003 Text Summarization
Workshop and Document Understanding Conference (DUC 2003), pages 85–92, Edmonton, Alberta.
D. Bikel, R. Schwartz, and R. Weischedel. 1999. An algorithm that learns what’s in a name. Machine
Learning, 34(1/3):211–231.
S. Blair-Goldensohn, D. Evans, V. Hatzivassiloglou, K. McKeown, A. Nenkova, R. Passonneau,
B. Schiffman, A. Schlaikjer, A. Siddharthan, and S. Siegelman. 2004. Columbia University
at DUC 2004. In Proceedings of the 2004 Document Understanding Conference (DUC 2004) at
HLT/NAACL 2004, pages 23–30, Boston, Massachusetts.
24
P. Brown, J. Cocke, S. Pietra, V. Pietra, F. Jelinek, J. Lafferty, R. Mercer, and P. Roossin. 1990. A
statistical approach to machine translation. Computational Linguistics, 16(2):79–85.
J. Carbonell and J. Goldstein. 1998. The use of MMR, diversity-based reranking for reordering
documents and producing summaries. In Proceedings of the 21st Annual International ACM SIGIR
Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR 1998), pages 335–336,
Melbourne, Australia.
Eugene Charniak. 2000. A Maximum-Entropy-Inspired Parser. In Proceedings of the First Meeting
of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (NAACL 2000),
pages 132–139, Seattle, Washington.
J. Clarke and M. Lapata. 2006. Models for sentence compression: A comparison across domains,
training requirements and evaluation measures. In Proceedings of the 21st International Confer-
ence on Computational Linguistics and 44th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational
Linguistics (COLING/ACL 2006), pages 377–384, Sydney, Australia.
J. Conroy, J. Schlesinger, and J. Goldstein. 2005. CLASSY query-based multi-document summariza-
tion. In Proceedings of the 2005 Document Understanding Conference (DUC-2005) at NLT/EMNLP
2005, Vancouver, Canada.
J. Conroy, J. Schlesinger, D. O’Leary, and J. Goldstein. 2006. Back to basics: CLASSY 2006. In
Proceedings of the 2006 Document Understanding Conference (DUC 2006) at HLT/NAACL 2006,
New York, New York.
D. Cutting, J. Pedersen, and P. Sibun. 1992. A practical part-of-speech tagger. In Proceedings of the
Third Conference on Applied Natural Language Processing, Trento, Italy.
Hoa Dang and Donna Harman. 2006. Proceedings of the 2006 Document Understanding Conference
(DUC 2006) at HLT/NAACL 2006.
B. Dorr and T. Gaasterland. this special issue, 2007. Exploiting aspectual features and connecting
words for summarization-inspired temporal-relation extraction. Information Processing and Man-
agement.
B. Dorr, D. Zajic, and R. Schwartz. 2003a. Cross-language headline generation for Hindi. ACM
Transactions on Asian Language Information Processing (TALIP), 2(3):270–289.
B. Dorr, D. Zajic, and R. Schwartz. 2003b. Hedge Trimmer: A parse-and-trim approach to headline
generation. In Proceedings of the HLT-NAACL 2003 Text Summarization Workshop and Document
Understanding Conference (DUC 2003), pages 1–8, Edmonton, Alberta.
T. Dunning. 1994. Statistical identification of language. Technical Report MCCS 94-273, New Mexico
State University.
T. Euler. 2002. Tailoring text using topic words: Selection and compression. In Proceedings of 13th
International Workshop on Database and Expert Systems Applications (DEXA 2002), pages 215–
222, Aix-en-Provence, France.
J. Goldstein, V. Mittal, J. Carbonell, and M. Kantrowitz. 2000. Multi-document summarization by
sentence extraction. In Proceedings of ANLP/NAACL 2000 Workshop on Automatic Summariza-
tion, pages 40–48.
D. Harman and M. Liberman. 1993. TIPSTER Complete. Linguistic Data Consortium (LDC),
Philadelphia.
25
H. Jing and K. McKeown. 2000. Cut and paste based text summarization. In Proceedings of the First
Meeting of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (NAACL
2000), pages 178–185, Seattle, Washington.
B. Klimt and Y. Yang. 2004. Introducing the Enron Corpus. In Proceedings of the First Conference
on Email and Anti-Spam (CEAS), Mountain View, California.
K. Knight and D. Marcu. 2000. Statistics-based summarization—step one: Sentence compression. In
Proceedings of the Seventeenth National Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI-2000), Austin,
Texas.
K. Knight and D. Marcu. 2002. Summarization beyond sentence extraction: A probabilistic approach
to sentence compression. Artificial Intelligence, 139(1):91–107.
M. Lapata. 2003. Probabilistic text structuring: Experiments with sentence ordering. In Proceedings
of the 42nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL 2004), pages
545–552, Barcelona, Spain.
David Dolan Lewis. 1999. An evaluation of phrasal and clustered representations on a text categoriza-
tion task. In Proceedings of the 15th Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research
and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR 1992), pages 37–50, Copenhagen, Denmark.
C.-Y. Lin and E. Hovy. 2003. Automatic evaluation of summaries using n-gram co-occurrence statis-
tics. In Proceedings of the 2003 Human Language Technology Conference and the North American
Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics Annual Meeting (HLT/NAACL 2003),
pages 71–78, Edmonton, Alberta.
I. Mårdh. 1980. Headlinese: On the Grammar of English Front Page Headlines. Malmo.
E. Mays, F. Damerau, and R. Mercer. 1990. Context-based spelling correction. In Proceedings of IBM
Natural Language ITL, pages 517–522, Paris, France.
S. Miller, L. Ramshaw, H. Fox, and R. Weischedel. 2000. A novel use of statistical parsing to extract
information from text. In Proceedings of the First Meeting of the North American Chapter of the
Association for Computational Linguistics (NAACL 2000), pages 226–233, Seattle, Washington.
S. Muresan, E. Tzoukermann, and J. Klavans. 2001. Combining linguistic and machine learning
techniques for email. In Proceedings of the ACL/EACL 2001 Workshop on Computational Natural
Language Learning (ConLL), pages 290–297, Toulouse, France.
N. Okazaki, Y. Matsuo, and M. Ishizuka. 2004. Improving chronological sentence ordering by prece-
dence relation. In Proceedings of the 20th International Conference on Computational Linguistics
(COLING 2004), pages 750–756, Geneva, Switzerland.
M. Porter. 1980. An algorithm for suffix stripping. Program, 14(3):130–137.
D. Radev, T. Allison, S. Blair-Goldensohn, J. Blitzer, A. Çelebi, S. Dimitrov, E. Drabek, A. Hakim,
W. Lam, D. Liu, J. Otterbacher, H. Qi, H. Saggion, S. Teufel, M. Topper, A. Winkel, and Z. Zhang.
2004. MEAD—a platform for multidocument multilingual text summarization. In Proceedings of
the 4th International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC 2004), Lisbon,
Portugal.
26
R. Schwartz, T. Imai, F. Jubala, L. Nguyen, and J. Makhoul. 1997. A maximum likelihood model
for topic classification of broadcast news. In Proceedings of the Fifth European Speech Communica-
tion Association Conference on Speech Communication and Technology (Eurospeech-97), Rhodes,
Greece.
S. Sista, R. Schwartz, T. Leek, and J. Makhoul. 2002. An algorithm for unsupervised topic discovery
from broadcast news stories. In Proceedings of the 2002 Human Language Technology Conference
(HLT), pages 99–103, San Diego, California.
J. Turner and E. Charniak. 2005. Supervised and unsupervised learning for sentence compression.
In Proceedings of the 43rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL
2005), pages 290–297, Ann Arbor, Michigan.
L. Vanderwende, H. Suzuki, and C. Brockett. 2006. Microsoft Research at DUC2006: Task-focused
summarization with sentence simplification and lexical expansion. In Proceedings of the 2006 Doc-
ument Understanding Conference (DUC 2006) at HLT/NAACL 2006, New York, New York.
A. Viterbi. 1967. Error bounds for convolution codes and an asymptotically optimal decoding algo-
rithm. IEEE Transactions on Information Theory, 13:260–269.
R. Wang, N. Stokes, W. Doran, E. Newman, J. Carthy, and J. Dunnion. 2005. Comparing Topiary-
style approaches to headline generation. In Lecture Notes in Computer Science: Advances in
Information Retrieval: 27th European Conference on IR Research (ECIR 2005), volume 3408,
Santiago de Compostela, Spain. Springer Berlin / Heidelberg.
D. Zajic, B. Dorr, and R. Schwartz. 2004. BBN/UMD at DUC-2004: Topiary. In Proceedings of
the 2004 Document Understanding Conference (DUC 2004) at NLT/NAACL 2004, pages 112–119,
Boston, Massachusetts.
D. Zajic, B. Dorr, J. Lin, and R. Schwartz. 2005a. UMD/BBN at MSE2005. In Proceedings of the
MSE2005 Track of the ACL 2005 Workshop on Intrinsic and Extrinsic Evaluation Measures for
MT and/or Summarization, Ann Arbor, Michigan.
D. Zajic, B. Dorr, R. Schwartz, C. Monz, and J. Lin. 2005b. A sentence-trimming approach to
multi-document summarization. In Proceedings of the 2005 Document Understanding Conference
(DUC-2005) at NLT/EMNLP 2005, pages 151–158, Vancouver, Canada.
D. Zajic. 2007. Multiple Alternative Sentence Compressions (MASC) as a Tool for Automatic Sum-
marization Tasks. Ph.D. thesis, University of Maryland, College Park.
L. Zhou and E. Hovy. 2003. Headline summarization at ISI. In Proceedings of the HLT-NAACL
2003 Text Summarization Workshop and Document Understanding Conference (DUC 2003), pages
174–178, Edmonton, Alberta.
27
</reference>
</article>
