<article>
	<preamble>compression_phrases_Prog-Linear-jair.pdf</preamble>
	<title>Journal of Artificial Intelligence Research 31 (2008) 399-429 Submitted 09/07; published 03/08Global Inference for Sentence Compression</title>
	<authors>not implemented yet</authors>
	<abstract>Abstract Sentence compression holds promise for many applications ranging from summarization to subtitle generation. Our work views sentence compression as an optimization problem and uses integer linear programming (ILP) to infer globally optimal compressions in the presence of linguistically motivated constraints. We show how previous formulations of sentence compression can be recast as ILPs and extend these models with novel global constraints. Experimental results on written and spoken texts demonstrate improvements over state-of-the-art models.</abstract>
	<reference>
Aho, A. V., & Ullman, J. D. (1969). Syntax directed translations and the pushdown assem-
bler. Journal of Computer and System Sciences, 3, 37–56.
Bangalore, S., Rambow, O., & Whittaker, S. (2000). Evaluation metrics for generation.
In Proceedings of the first International Conference on Natural Language Generation,
pp. 1–8, Mitzpe Ramon, Israel.
Barzilay, R., & Lapata, M. (2006). Aggregation via set partitioning for natural language
generation. In Proceedings of the Human Language Technology Conference of the
North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 359–
366, New York, NY, USA.
Bramsen, P., Deshpande, P., Lee, Y. K., & Barzilay, R. (2006). Inducing temporal graphs.
In Proceedings of the 2006 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language
Processing, pp. 189–198, Sydney, Australia.
Briscoe, E. J., & Carroll, J. (2002). Robust accurate statistical annotation of general text. In
Proceedings of the Third International Conference on Language Resources and Eval-
uation, pp. 1499–1504, Las Palmas, Gran Canaria.
Charniak, E. (2000). A maximum-entropy-inspired parser. In Proceedings of the 1st North
American Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 132–
139, Seattle, WA, USA.
Clarke, J., & Lapata, M. (2006). Models for sentence compression: A comparison across
domains, training requirements and evaluation measures. In Proceedings of the 21st
International Conference on Computational Linguistics and 44th Annual Meeting of
the Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 377–384, Sydney, Australia.
Clarkson, P., & Rosenfeld, R. (1997). Statistical language modeling using the CMU–
Cambridge toolkit. In Proceedings of Eurospeech’97, pp. 2707–2710, Rhodes, Greece.
426
Global Inference for Sentence Compression
Cormen, T. H., Leiserson, C. E., & Rivest, R. L. (1992). Intoduction to Algorithms. The
MIT Press.
Corston-Oliver, S. (2001). Text Compaction for Display on Very Small Screens. In Proceed-
ings of the Workshop on Automatic Summarization at the 2nd Meeting of the North
American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 89–98, Pitts-
burgh, PA, USA.
Crammer, K., & Singer, Y. (2003). Ultraconservative online algorithms for multiclass prob-
lems. Journal of Machine Learning Research, 3, 951–991.
Dantzig, G. B. (1963). Linear Programming and Extensions. Princeton University Press,
Princeton, NJ, USA.
Denis, P., & Baldridge, J. (2007). Joint determination of anaphoricity and coreference
resolution using integer programming. In Human Language Technologies 2007: The
Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Lin-
guistics; Proceedings of the Main Conference, pp. 236–243, Rochester, NY.
Dras, M. (1999). Tree Adjoining Grammar and the Reluctant Paraphrasing of Text. Ph.D.
thesis, Macquarie University.
Galley, M., & McKeown, K. (2007). Lexicalized markov grammars for sentence compression.
In In Proceedings of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational
Linguistics, pp. 180–187, Rochester, NY, USA.
Gomory, R. E. (1960). Solving linear programming problems in integers. In Bellman,
R., & Hall, M. (Eds.), Combinatorial analysis, Proceedings of Symposia in Applied
Mathematics, Vol. 10, Providence, RI, USA.
Grefenstette, G. (1998). Producing Intelligent Telegraphic Text Reduction to Provide an
Audio Scanning Service for the Blind. In Hovy, E., & Radev, D. R. (Eds.), Proceedings
of the AAAI Symposium on Intelligent Text Summarization, pp. 111–117, Stanford,
CA, USA.
Hori, C., & Furui, S. (2004). Speech summarization: an approach through word extraction
and a method for evaluation. IEICE Transactions on Information and Systems, E87-
D(1), 15–25.
Jing, H. (2000). Sentence reduction for automatic text summarization. In Proceedings of
the 6th Applied Natural Language Processing Conference, pp. 310–315, Seattle,WA,
USA.
Knight, K., & Marcu, D. (2002). Summarization beyond sentence extraction: a probabilistic
approach to sentence compression. Artificial Intelligence, 139(1), 91–107.
Land, A. H., & Doig, A. G. (1960). An automatic method for solving discrete programming
problems. Econometrica, 28, 497–520.
Lin, C.-Y. (2003). Improving summarization performance by sentence compression — a pilot
study. In Proceedings of the 6th International Workshop on Information Retrieval with
Asian Languages, pp. 1–8, Sapporo, Japan.
Lin, D. (2001). LaTaT: Language and text analysis tools. In Proceedings of the first Human
Language Technology Conference, pp. 222–227, San Francisco, CA, USA.
427
Clarke & Lapata
Marciniak, T., & Strube, M. (2005). Beyond the pipeline: Discrete optimization in NLP. In
Proceedings of the Ninth Conference on Computational Natural Language Learning,
pp. 136–143, Ann Arbor, MI, USA.
McDonald, R. (2006). Discriminative sentence compression with soft syntactic constraints.
In Proceedings of the 11th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for
Computational Linguistics, Trento, Italy.
McDonald, R., Crammer, K., & Pereira, F. (2005a). Flexible text segmentation with struc-
tured multilabel classification. In Proceedings of Human Language Technology Con-
ference and Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, pp.
987–994, Vancouver, BC, Canada.
McDonald, R., Crammer, K., & Pereira, F. (2005b). Online large-margin training of de-
pendency parsers. In 43rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational
Linguistics, pp. 91–98, Ann Arbor, MI, USA.
Nemhauser, G. L., & Wolsey, L. A. (1988). Integer and Combinatorial Optimization. Wiley-
Interscience series in discrete mathematicals and opitmization. Wiley, New York, NY,
USA.
Nguyen, M. L., Shimazu, A., Horiguchi, S., Ho, T. B., & Fukushi, M. (2004). Probabilistic
sentence reduction using support vector machines. In Proceedings of the 20th inter-
national conference on Computational Linguistics, pp. 743–749, Geneva, Switzerland.
Press, W. H., Teukolsky, S. A., Vetterling, W. T., & Flannery, B. P. (1992). Numerical
Recipes in C: The Art of Scientific Computing. Cambridge University Press, New
York, NY, USA.
Punyakanok, V., Roth, D., Yih, W., & Zimak, D. (2004). Semantic role labeling via inte-
ger linear programming inference. In Proceedings of the International Conference on
Computational Linguistics, pp. 1346–1352, Geneva, Switzerland.
Riedel, S., & Clarke, J. (2006). Incremental integer linear programming for non-projective
dependency parsing. In Proceedings of the 2006 Conference on Empirical Methods in
Natural Language Processing, pp. 129–137, Sydney, Australia.
Riezler, S., King, T. H., Crouch, R., & Zaenen, A. (2003). Statistical sentence condensation
using ambiguity packing and stochastic disambiguation methods for lexical-functional
grammar. In Human Language Technology Conference and the 3rd Meeting of the
North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 118–
125, Edmonton, Canada.
Roark, B. (2001). Probabilistic top-down parsing and language modeling. Computational
Linguistics, 27(2), 249–276.
Roth, D. (1998). Learning to resolve natural language ambiguities: A unified approach. In
In Proceedings of the 15th of the American Association for Artificial Intelligence, pp.
806–813, Madison, WI, USA.
Roth, D., & Yih, W. (2004). A linear programming formulation for global inference in
natural language tasks. In Proceedings of the Annual Conference on Computational
Natural Language Learning, pp. 1–8, Boston, MA, USA.
428
Global Inference for Sentence Compression
Roth, D., & Yih, W. (2005). Integer linear programming inference for conditional random
fields. In Proceedings of the International Conference on Machine Learning, pp. 737–
744, Bonn.
Sarawagi, S., & Cohen, W. W. (2004). Semi-markov conditional random fields for informa-
tion extraction. In Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems, Vancouver,
BC, Canada.
Shieber, S., & Schabes, Y. (1990). Synchronous tree-adjoining grammars. In Proceed-
ings of the 13th International Conference on Computational Linguistics, pp. 253–258,
Helsinki, Finland.
Turner, J., & Charniak, E. (2005). Supervised and unsupervised learning for sentence
compression. In Proceedings of the 43rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Com-
putational Linguistics, pp. 290–297, Ann Arbor, MI, USA.
Vandeghinste, V., & Pan, Y. (2004). Sentence compression for automated subtitling: A
hybrid approach. In Marie-Francine Moens, S. S. (Ed.), Text Summarization Branches
Out: Proceedings of the ACL-04 Workshop, pp. 89–95, Barcelona, Spain.
Williams, H. P. (1999). Model Building in Mathematical Programming (4th edition). Wiley.
Winston, W. L., & Venkataramanan, M. (2003). Introduction to Mathematical Program-
ming: Applications and Algorithms (4th edition). Duxbury.
Zajic, D., Door, B. J., Lin, J., & Schwartz, R. (2007). Multi-candidate reduction: Sentence
compression as a tool for document summarization tasks. Information Processing
Management Special Issue on Summarization, 43(6), 1549–1570.
429
</reference>
</article>
