<article>
	<preamble>marcu_statistics_sentence_pass_one.pdf</preamble>
	<title>Statistics-Based Summarization — Step One: Sentence CompressionKevin Knight and Daniel Marcu</title>
	<authors>not implemented yet</authors>
	<abstract>Abstract When humans produce summaries of documents, they do not simply extract sentences and concatenate them. Rather, they create new sentences that are grammati- cal, that cohere with one another, and that capture the most salient pieces of information in the original doc- ument. Given that large collections of text/abstract pairs are available online, it is now possible to envision algorithms that are trained to mimic this process. In this paper, we focus on sentence compression, a sim- pler version of this larger challenge. We aim to achieve two goals simultaneously: our compressions should be grammatical, and they should retain the most impor- tant pieces of information. These two goals can con- ﬂict. We devise both noisy-channel and decision-tree approaches to the problem, and we evaluate results against manual compressions and a simple baseline.</abstract>
	<reference>
Barzilay, R.; McKeown, K.; and Elhadad, M. 1999.
Information fusion in the context of multi-document
summarization. In Proceedings of the 37th Annual
Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguis-
tics (ACL–99), 550–557.
Berger, A., and Laﬀerty, J. 1999. Information retrieval
as statistical translation. In Proceedings of the 22nd
Conference on Research and Development in Informa-
tion Retrieval (SIGIR–99), 222–229.
Brown, P.; Della Pietra, S.; Della Pietra, V.; and Mer-
cer, R. 1993. The mathematics of statistical ma-
chine translation: Parameter estimation. Computa-
tional Linguistics 19(2):263–311.
Church, K. 1988. A stochastic parts program and noun
phrase parser for unrestricted text. In Proceedings of
the Second Conference on Applied Natural Language
Processing, 136–143.
Collins, M. 1997. Three generative, lexicalized mod-
els for statistical parsing. In Proceedings of the 35th
Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational
Linguistics (ACL–97), 16–23.
Grefenstette, G. 1998. Producing intelligent tele-
graphic text reduction to provide an audio scanning
service for the blind. In Working Notes of the AAAI
Spring Symposium on Intelligent Text Summarization,
111–118.
Jelinek, F. 1997. Statistical Methods for Speech Recog-
nition. The MIT Press.
Jing, H., and McKeown, K. 1999. The decomposition
of human-written summary sentences. In Proceedings
of the 22nd Conference on Research and Development
in Information Retrieval (SIGIR–99).
Knight, K., and Graehl, J. 1998. Machine transliter-
ation. Computational Linguistics 24(4):599–612.
Langkilde, I. 2000. Forest-based statistical sentence
generation. In Proceedings of the 1st Annual Meeting
of the North American Chapter of the Association for
Computational Linguistics.
Linke-Ellis, N. 1999. Closed captioning in Amer-
ica: Looking beyond compliance. In Proceedings of
the TAO Workshop on TV Closed Captions for the
hearing impaired people, 43–59.
Magerman, D. 1995. Statistical decision-tree models
for parsing. In Proceedings of the 33rd Annual Meeting
of the Association for Computational Linguistics, 276–
283.
Mani, I., and Maybury, M., eds. 1999. Advances in
Automatic Text Summarization. The MIT Press.
Mani, I.; Gates, B.; and Bloedorn, E. 1999. Improving
summaries by revising them. In Proceedings of the 37th
Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational
Linguistics, 558–565.
McKeown, K.; Klavans, J.; Hatzivassiloglou, V.;
Barzilay, R.; and Eskin, E. 1999. Towards multidoc-
ument summarization by reformulation: Progress and
prospects. In Proceedings of the Sixteenth National
Conference on Artiﬁcial Intelligence (AAAI–99).
Quinlan, J. 1993. C4.5: Programs for Machine Learn-
ing. San Mateo, CA: Morgan Kaufmann Publishers.
Robert-Ribes, J.; Pfeiﬀer, S.; Ellison, R.; and Burn-
ham, D. 1999. Semi-automatic captioning of TV pro-
grams, an Australian perspective. In Proceedings of
the TAO Workshop on TV Closed Captions for the
hearing impaired people, 87–100.
Witbrock, M., and Mittal, V. 1999. Ultra-
summarization: A statistical approach to generating
highly condensed non-extractive summaries. In Pro-
ceedings of the 22nd International Conference on Re-
search and Development in Information Retrieval (SI-
GIR’99), Poster Session, 315–316.
</reference>
</article>
